Hamstring curls in a quad prone position.
We're going to put the weight behind our knee.
Make sure you've got a weight that you're going to be able to control and keep in there.
Some people like the, you can get balls, medicine balls, little weighted balls to put in there as well, but this will work just fine with our hands underneath our shoulders.
Knees square with the hips.
And we're going to contract exhale and inhale release.
It is not necessary to come all the way back down, because then I lose neutral posture.
You want to maintain neutral posture, this is kind of a half plank.
So we exhale, we contract, we don't want to go any higher than the hip, after that we're involving the low back and the exercise is over.
Primary focus remember is hamstring, passes into the glut.
Leave the ankle, the foot, nice and soft, don't excessively point or flex.
It's not going to put any more workload in there.
You've already got resistance to the movement, you've got position of the movement.
Nice slow and controlled, up two, down two.
Working within ten to fifteen reps, three sets.